<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Blog EN</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 16:35:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4</generator>
		<item>
		<title>A quick guide to promoting black friday and cyber monday sales</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/a-quick-guide-to-promoting-black-friday-and-cyber-monday-sales/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/a-quick-guide-to-promoting-black-friday-and-cyber-monday-sales/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 16:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=18983</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Black Friday and Cyber Monday are literally days away.  Many online merchants will process their largest number of orders during the weekend. If you’ve downloaded our ecommerce holiday guide, you already have great ideas for promotions you can run. Once &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/a-quick-guide-to-promoting-black-friday-and-cyber-monday-sales/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Black Friday and Cyber Monday are literally days away.  Many online merchants will process their largest number of orders during the weekend. If you’ve downloaded our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-holiday-guide" target="_blank">ecommerce holiday guide</a>, you already have great ideas for promotions you can run.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img class="wp-image-18984 aligncenter" title="BP_Sale" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/BP_Sale.png" alt="" width="540" height="283" />Once you’ve set up your sales, getting the word out is just as important. Check out this quick guide to promoting Black Friday and Cyber Monday sales.</p>
<p><span id="more-18983"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="color: #ed2279;">1.</span> Homepage Slider or Banner</span></h2>
<p>The best place to tell customers about sales is on your homepage. Both visitors looking for sales and those simply browsing your shop will be greeted with your sale announcement. Ensure the slider or banner is linked to your sale products, so customers can start shopping immediately.</p>
<p>BACK OFFICE &gt; MODULES &gt; IMAGE SLIDER FOR YOUR HOMEPAGE &gt; CONFIGURE</p>
<h2><span style="color: #000000;"><strong><span style="color: #ed2279;">2.</span> Send out an email blast</strong></span></h2>
<p>Delivering your sale directly into your customer’s inbox will put your sale directly within their reach. Entice your customer to open your email with a tempting subject line.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that more and more customers are opening emails on mobile devices. Be sure your emails can easily be read on smaller screens and that links open on the mobile version of your website, if your website isn’t responsive. Start promoting your sales with the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/4932-newsletter-statistics.html" target="_blank">Newsletter and Statistics Module by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
<h2 style="font-weight: inherit;" dir="ltr"><span style="color: #000000;"><strong><span style="color: #ed2279;">3.</span> Social Media is your Best Friend</strong></span></h2>
<p style="font-weight: inherit;" dir="ltr">Connect with customers through their favorite social media channel. Keep in mind that many other companies may also be offering their Black Friday / Cyber Monday deals, so ensure your ads contain:</p>
<ol style="font-weight: inherit;">
<li>Enticing deals</li>
<li>Targeted hashtags, specifically: #blackfriday #cybermonday #sale</li>
<li>Images (promoting products or holiday themed)</li>
</ol>
<h2><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="color: #ed2279;">4.</span> List your Sale</span></h2>
<p>Once you’ve notified your <em>current</em> customers about your sale, it’s time to reach out to <em>potential</em> customers. List your sale on coupon sites like <a href="http://www.retailmenot.com/" target="_blank">RetailMeNot </a>or on <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/coupons/" target="_blank">Coupon Forums</a> to gain more visibility with online shoppers. Everyone is looking to save money and start their holiday shopping. Make your sale as easy to find as possible.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="color: #ed2279;">5.</span> Purchase Ads</span></h2>
<p>If your budget allows, purchase advertising. Running ads during the holiday season may not be cheap but they give you the best chance at gaining even visibility among holiday shoppers. In this day and age, you’re not limited to search engine ads. Many social media platforms offer business accounts and the ability to purchase ads. Although these advertising channels are not traditional, they have a large reach. Try <a href="https://www.facebook.com/about/ads/" target="_blank">Facebook </a>and <a href="https://support.twitter.com/groups/58-advertising/topics/242-welcome-to-twitter-ads/articles/20170393-how-twitter-ads-can-help-your-business" target="_blank">Twitter Ads</a> or even <a href="https://business.pinterest.com/en/promoted-pins" target="_blank">Promoted Pins on Pinterest</a>.</p>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
<p dir="ltr">After this short read, you’re ready to get out there and promote your Black Friday and Cyber Monday sales. Are there any last minute tips you’d like to share? Tell us in the comments below. Not an online merchant yet? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">Download PrestaShop’s</a> shopping cart software to get started!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/a-quick-guide-to-promoting-black-friday-and-cyber-monday-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 tests to run before launching your ecommerce site</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-tests-to-run-before-launching-your-ecommerce-site/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-tests-to-run-before-launching-your-ecommerce-site/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 16:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Magali Ferber</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=18946</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Have you ever visited an online store that looks like it accidently launched in the middle of construction? For many merchants, it’s no accident. New storeowners may sometimes be unaware of everything that should be tested before their store goes &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-tests-to-run-before-launching-your-ecommerce-site/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-18948" title="check-list4" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/check-list4-1024x537.png" alt="header" width="584" height="306" />Have you ever visited an online store that looks like it accidently launched in the middle of construction? For many merchants, it’s no accident. New storeowners may sometimes be unaware of everything that should be tested before their store goes live.</p>
<p>From device compatibility to creating user scenarios, this article covers all of the essential tests to guarantee a successful launch. Once you finish reading, you’ll know how to effectively switch from “Pardon our dust” to “Open for business!”<span id="more-18946"></span></p>
<h4 style="color: #5c9435;">1. COMPATIBILITY &amp; RESPONSIVENESS</h4>
<p>The first thing to check on any website before launching is its compatibility and responsiveness, to ensure customers will be able to browse the store with every program and on every device available to them.</p>
<p>- <strong>Browser Compatibility</strong>: a browser compatibility test, such as the one available at <a href="https://crossbrowsertesting.com/" target="_blank">CrossBrowserTesting</a>, will check if your site is compatible on all of these browsers: Internet Explorer, Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox and Safari.<br />
- <strong>Website Responsiveness</strong>: a responsiveness test, like the one offered at <a href="http://responsivetest.net/" target="_blank">ResponsiveTest</a>, will display your website on screen sizes of the most popular desktops, tablets and phones to ensure your website displays beautifully on all of them.</p>
<h4 style="color: #5c9435;">2. CONTENT</h4>
<p>Next, double, triple and quadruple check your site’s content. And by content, I mean anything that visitors can see, read and hear. Confusing or unprofessional site content could affect your store’s credibility and negatively impact your sales, so make sure to review:<br />
<span style="margin-left: 15px;"><br />
- Spelling and grammar errors<br />
- Formatting and homogeneity of the paragraphs, lists, and headings<br />
- Company contact information<br />
- Image sizes, positions, and usefulness<br />
- Product information, prices, descriptions, images, sizes available, etc.<br />
</span></p>
<h4 style="color: #5c9435;">3. FUNCTIONALITY</h4>
<p>Because your store is an interactive experience, it is not enough to just look at your pages to test if they are spot-on, you must interact with them and play with different scenarios. Here is a list of situations to double check to make sure the basic functionalities are working properly:<br />
<span style="margin-left: 15px;"><br />
- Click on every link, button, image or text to make sure it takes you to the right page.<br />
- Check that external links, such as social media links, open on a separate tab or window.<br />
- Create test customer accounts.<br />
- Place test orders using all the payment methods you have available.<br />
- Delete the test orders once you are ready to launch.<br />
- If you have a Multilanguage store, test the different languages.<br />
- If you sell internationally, test the different currencies.<br />
</span></p>
<h4 style="color: #5c9435;">4. USER EXPERIENCE (BONUS!)</h4>
<p>An extra step to test before your online store’s successful launch is user experience, or in other words, ensuring that the journey within your website flows correctly. There are three levels at which you can test user experience. Run these tests every time you make a significant change on your website.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Test it yourself.</strong> Imagine that you are a customer that first visits the store. Ask yourself questions. Create situations to test user experiences such as finding relevant information, purchasing or searching for a specific product.</li>
<li><strong>Have your friends test it.</strong> Watch them navigate your site and ask them to execute certain actions or find specific pieces of information. Try to capture moments in which they get stuck and why they do so. Sometimes, even a simple modification in content, like a clearer call to action, can help solve these “stuck moments” and significantly improve your user experience.</li>
<li><strong>Have a professional service test it.</strong> User testing through websites such as <a href="http://www.usertesting.com/" target="_blank">UserTesting.com</a> are a great investment. The concept of their test is the same as the one above, but the difference is that your website will be tested by many different participants. This will help you confirm that your concept and messages are easily understandable throughout the user journey on your online Store.</li>
</ol>
<h4 style="color: #5c9435;">5. THE LAUNCH</h4>
<p>That’s it &#8211; you are now ready to launch! PrestaShop users, can activate your Online Store from your back-office, under the “Preferences / Maintenance” page, and setting the “Enable Shop” option to YES. Congratulations! Your store is officially open for business.</p>
<p>Not a PrestaShop merchant? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">Download</a> PrestaShop to start launching your online store.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-tests-to-run-before-launching-your-ecommerce-site/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holiday Tool Kit for your Ecommerce Site</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/holiday-tool-kit-for-your-ecommerce-site/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/holiday-tool-kit-for-your-ecommerce-site/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 11:13:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=18931</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With the holidays just around the corner, there’s a buzz of excitement in the air. Each shop is decorated with festive home pages, ready to welcome this season’s holiday shoppers. To help you make the most of the shopping season, &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/holiday-tool-kit-for-your-ecommerce-site/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-18938" title="holiday-guide-main" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/holiday-guide-main-1024x537.png" alt="header" width="584" height="306" /></p>
<p>With the holidays just around the corner, there’s a buzz of excitement in the air. Each shop is decorated with festive home pages, ready to welcome this season’s holiday shoppers. To help you make the most of the shopping season, we’re sharing this holiday tool kit to help prepare your ecommerce site. Let’s get started!</p>
<p><span id="more-18931"></span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a style="color: #af3736;" href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/8300-sendinblue.html" target="_blank">SendinBlue</a></h2>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/8300-sendinblue.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-18952" style="color: #333333; font-style: normal; line-height: 24.375px; margin-top: 0.4em; margin-right: 2em; text-align: center;" title="sendinblue" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/sendinblue.png" alt="sendinblue" width="254" height="216" align="left" /></a></p>
<p><strong style="color: #343943;">LEVERAGE EMAIL MARKETING</strong></p>
<p>Reach out to subscribers in your email list to notify them of any sales or promotions you may be running. With SendinBlue’s all-in-one module, easily create stunning emails that captures your customer’s attention. Want even more features? SendinBlue allows you to segment customers to further optimize your email campaigns. Then they help you track campaigns to measure its effectiveness. Send up to 300 emails per day for free! To get started,<a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/sendinblue.png" target="_blank"> download the SendinBlue module</a> and sign up for your account.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a style="color: #af3736;" href="http://www.verified-reviews.co.uk/tracker.php?tracker=Page_partner_Prestashop&amp;url=http://www.verified-reviews.co.uk/index.php?page=mod_inscription" target="_blank">Verified Reviews</a></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.verified-reviews.co.uk/tracker.php?tracker=Page_partner_Prestashop&amp;url=http://www.verified-reviews.co.uk/index.php?page=mod_inscription" target="_blank"><img class="size-full wp-image-18953" style="color: #333333; font-style: normal; line-height: 24.375px; margin-top: 0.4em; margin-right: 2em; text-align: center;" title="rating" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/rating.png" alt="Verified Reviews" width="235" height="200" align="left" /></a></p>
<p><strong style="color: #343943;">BUILD SOCIAL CREDIBILITY</strong></p>
<p>Once shoppers arrive at your website, your task is to convert these visitors into paying customers. Use customer reviews to build trust in your website. Today, 85% of Internet users read customer reviews before making an online purchase, and 63% prefer to buy from a site that displays reviews. <a href="http://www.verified-reviews.co.uk/tracker.php?tracker=Page_partner_Prestashop&amp;url=http://www.verified-reviews.co.uk/index.php?page=mod_inscription" target="_blank">Verified Reviews</a> effortlessly helps you build trust in both your products and website with a platform that facilitates the collection, moderation and publication of customer reviews. No matter the size of your online shop, this is an important tool when acquiring both new and old holiday shoppers.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a style="color: #af3736;" href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/administration-tools-prestashop-modules/18033-erpillicopresta.html" target="_blank">1-Click ERP by illicoPresta</a></h2>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/administration-tools-prestashop-modules/18033-erpillicopresta.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-18954" style="color: #333333; font-style: normal; line-height: 24.375px; margin-top: 0.4em; margin-right: 2em; text-align: center;" title="illicopresta" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/illicopresta.png" alt="illicopresta" width="254" height="216" align="left" /></a></p>
<p><strong style="color: #343943;">MANAGE HOLIDAY LOGISTICS</strong></p>
<p>As you start receiving more and more holiday orders, it’s important to process them in a timely fashion. Effortlessly manage both your inventory and orders with Illico Presta’s integrated back-office suite. Get a comprehensive overview of your shop with intuitive screens that display stocks levels, order content, and carrier options. Then save time processing your orders with options to bulk edit invoices and delivery slips or more importantly, automate shipping. Install <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/administration-tools-prestashop-modules/18033-erpillicopresta.html" target="_blank">1-Click ERP by Illico Presta</a> directly from your back office today to get your first month free.</p>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
<p>Want to learn more about setting up your shop for the holidays? Download our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-holiday-guide" target="_blank">2014 Ecommerce Holiday Planning Guide</a> for a comprehensive guide to mastering the holidays.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/holiday-tool-kit-for-your-ecommerce-site/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Security Alert on the PayPal Europe module: Action required by December 3, 2014</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/security-alert-on-the-paypal-europe-module-action-required-by-december-3-2014/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/security-alert-on-the-paypal-europe-module-action-required-by-december-3-2014/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 15:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Quentin Audrain</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=18923</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello PrestaShop Community, An industry-wide security issue with SSL V3 has impacted PayPal. As a reminder, SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) is a cryptographic protocol designed to provide communication security over the internet. This specific SSL V3 issue is known in &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/security-alert-on-the-paypal-europe-module-action-required-by-december-3-2014/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-18926" title="paypal_banner" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/paypal_banner-1024x537.png" alt="PayPal" width="584" height="306" />Hello PrestaShop Community,</p>
<p>An industry-wide security issue with SSL V3 has impacted PayPal. As a reminder, SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) is a cryptographic protocol designed to provide communication security over the internet. This specific SSL V3 issue is known in the industry as <a href="https://www.openssl.org/~bodo/ssl-poodle.pdf" target="_blank">POODLE</a>.</p>
<p>As a result, the PayPal Europe module for PrestaShop will need to be updated before December 3, 2014. We believe this update will only take you a few minutes and we encourage you to make the update as soon as possible.</p>
<p><span id="more-18923"></span></p>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">If you have not edited your module files</span></em></p>
<p>Go to the modules section of the back office of your store and update the module with the automatic tool. <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/download/pdf/PrestaShop_POODLE_EN.pdf" target="_blank">See the tutorial here</a>.</p>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">If you have edited your module files</span></em></p>
<p>Please follow<a href="http://www.prestashop.com/download/pdf/PayPal_SSL_to_TLS.pdf" target="_blank"> our documentation</a> to make the update. This will only take a couple of minutes.</p>
<p>PayPal is providing regular updates to their community on <a href="https://www.paypal-community.com/t5/PayPal-Forward/UPDATE-PayPal-Response-to-SSL-v3-Vulnerability-aka-POODLE/ba-p/902239" target="_blank">their blog</a>. If you have additional questions, please contact <a href="https://ppmts.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/1182/session/L3RpbWUvMTQxNjIyMTUxNy9zaWQvRVlua2tFN20%3D" target="_blank">Customer Support</a> at PayPal.</p>
<p>Thank you,<br />
The PrestaShop Product Team</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/security-alert-on-the-paypal-europe-module-action-required-by-december-3-2014/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Essential eCommerce Metrics for Google Analytics</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 13:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kunle Campbell</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=18891</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To begin with, let’s assume that you have been running your eCommerce site for a while and have the most basic eCommerce metrics tracking set up in your Google Analytics account like: Transactions Transaction Revenue Transaction Shipping Transaction Tax Item &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-18892" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/google-analytics-ecommerce-1-1024x537.png" alt="" width="584" height="306" /></p>
<p>To begin with, let’s assume that you have been running your eCommerce site for a while and have the most basic eCommerce metrics tracking set up in your Google Analytics account like:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>Transactions</li>
<li>Transaction Revenue</li>
<li>Transaction Shipping</li>
<li>Transaction Tax</li>
<li>Item Quantity</li>
<li>Unique Purchases</li>
<li>Item Revenue</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>This post aims to cover 10 complementary but essential metrics that should be tracked in Google Analytics for deeper insight into performance and users’ flow through the conversion funnel to enable you view your online retail business from a different angle. <span id="more-18891"></span>They are:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="color: #444444;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#Buy-to-Detail-Rate"><span style="color: #333333;">Buy-to-Detail Rate</span></a></span></li>
<li><span style="color: #444444;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#Internal-Promotion-Clicks-and-Views"><span style="color: #333333;">Internal Promotion Clicks and Views</span></a></span></li>
<li><span style="color: #444444;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#Product-Adds-To-Cart"><span style="color: #333333;">Product Adds To Cart</span></a></span></li>
<li><span style="color: #444444;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#Product-Removes-From-Cart"><span style="color: #333333;">Product Removes From Cart</span></a></span></li>
<li><span style="color: #444444;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#Product-Checkouts"><span style="color: #333333;">Product Checkouts</span></a></span></li>
<li><span style="color: #444444;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#Cost-Per-Acquisition-CPA"><span style="color: #333333;">Cost Per Acquisition (CPA)</span></a></span></li>
<li><span style="color: #444444;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#Product-Refunds"><span style="color: #333333;">Product Refunds</span></a></span></li>
<li><span style="color: #444444;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#Customer-Lifetime-Value"><span style="color: #333333;">Customer Lifetime Value</span></a></span></li>
<li><span style="color: #444444;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#Repeat-Purchase-Rate"><span style="color: #333333;">Repeat Purchase Rate</span></a></span></li>
<li><span style="color: #444444;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/#Revenue-Per-Session"><span style="color: #333333;">Revenue Per Session</span></a></span></li>
</ol>
<p>Some of these metrics can be tracked with the newly introduced <a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/enhanced-ecommerce" target="_blank">Enhanced eCommerce </a>tracking, whilst the others can be found on tables and by setting up custom events. Let’s have a look at each metric in some more detail.<br />
<a name="Buy-to-Detail-Rate"></a></p>
<h4><span style="color: #f7981d;"><strong>1. Buy-to-Detail Rate</strong></span></h4>
<p>This is derived as unique purchases divided by views of product detail pages (Enhanced Ecommerce). It can be found under:<br />
<strong>Ecommerce -&gt; Product Performance report</strong><br />
<img class="size-full wp-image-18893 alignnone" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/Metrics-for-Google-Analytics-1.png" alt="" width="580" height="358" /><br />
This metric can help you answer the following question:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">• For what products users are more likely to convert/purchase after looking at the product details?</p>
<p><a name="Internal-Promotion-Clicks-and-Views"></a></p>
<h4><span style="color: #f7981d;"><strong>2. Internal Promotion Clicks and Views.</strong></span></h4>
<p>This is an essential metric to effectively track and decide whether to run internal promotions in your store and would like to see:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>The most viewed promotions</li>
<li>The most clicked promotions</li>
<li>The Click-through-rate (CTR) of each promotion (Internal Promotion CTR)</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>These set of metrics are located under:<br />
<strong>Ecommerce-&gt;Marketing-&gt;Internal Promotion:</strong></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18894" title="Metrics for Google Analytics 2" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/Metrics-for-Google-Analytics-2.png" alt="" width="580" height="182" /><br />
<a name="Product-Adds-To-Cart"></a></p>
<h4><strong><span style="color: #f7981d;">3. Product Adds To Cart</span></strong></h4>
<p>This is a must-have metric as it shows the number of times shoppers’ added products to their shopping carts. It could be tracked either as part of enhanced ecommerce tracking or by setting up the event tracking associated with users’ clicks on add-to-cart buttons.</p>
<p>When using enhanced ecommerce tracking this metric is available under:<br />
<strong>Ecommerce-&gt;Shopping Analysis-&gt;Product List Performance</strong></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18895" title="Metrics for Google Analytics 3" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/Metrics-for-Google-Analytics-3.png" alt="" width="580" height="246" /></p>
<p>Having this metric in place provides you with the ability to analyze not only how many times products are added to cart but also why some products have higher conversion to purchase rates than the others.<br />
<a name="Product-Removes-From-Cart"></a></p>
<h4><span style="color: #f7981d;"><strong>4. Product Removes From Cart</strong></span></h4>
<p>This metric shows the number of times products have been removed from shopping carts. It can be tracked as part of Enhanced Ecommerce Tracking or can be set up as an event in event tracking that specifically tracks product removals from cart. Be sure to look out for products that are added to cart and then removed more often than others.</p>
<p>Track ‘<strong>Average</strong> <strong>Removes from Cart Rate’</strong>, which equals<br />
Total Removes from Cart / Adds to Cart.<br />
<a name="Product-Checkouts"></a></p>
<h4><span style="color: #f7981d;"><strong>5. Product Checkouts</strong></span></h4>
<p>Similar to product adds-to-cart, Product Checkouts show the number of times products were included at checkout. Product Checkout Tracking can be set up with Enhanced Ecommerce Tracking or with Event Tracking of clicks on the ‘Proceed to Checkout’ Button.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18896" title="Metrics for Google Analytics 4" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/Metrics-for-Google-Analytics-4.png" alt="" width="580" height="225" /></p>
<p>Important note is that: Products that proceed to checkout but unsuccessful orders should be further analyzed.<br />
<a name="Cost-Per-Acquisition-CPA"></a></p>
<h4><span style="color: #f7981d;"><strong>6. Cost Per Acquisition (CPA)</strong></span></h4>
<p>This is an essential metric that should be calculated and measured from two perspectives:</p>
<ol>
<li>What CPA can you afford, that will at the same time allow your business stay afloat?</li>
<li>What is your actual CPA after media traffic costs?</li>
</ol>
<p>Look at both figures and compare against each other:<br />
<strong>Planned CPA for Each Media Channel vs. Actual Spent CPA</strong></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18897" title="Metrics for Google Analytics 5" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/Metrics-for-Google-Analytics-5.png" alt="" width="580" height="157" /><br />
<a name="Product-Refunds"></a></p>
<h4><strong><span style="color: #f7981d;">7. Product Refunds</span></strong></h4>
<p>Available as part of Enhanced Ecommerce Tracking, this metric shows the number of times refunds were issued. Keep an eye on the <strong>Ecommerce-&gt;Product Performance</strong> report to spot products that have a high <strong>refund-to-purchase rate</strong> (which can be calculated as, total value of product refunds divided by product revenue).</p>
<p><a name="Customer-Lifetime-Value"></a></p>
<h4><strong><span style="color: #f7981d;">8. Customer Lifetime Value</span></strong></h4>
<p>This specific metric is not readily available in any report, however it is very useful and meaningful as it shows the value of repeat customers and how much they bring into your business. Create the following Advanced Segment to view users that have made more than 1 purchase on your site:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18898" title="Metrics for Google Analytics 6" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/Metrics-for-Google-Analytics-6.png" alt="" width="580" height="260" /></p>
<p>By looking at the revenue totals from the ‘repeat customer segment’ in Analytics, you will be able to answer the question:</p>
<ol>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>How much can you afford to pay for a planned acquisition (your planned CPA), knowing you can make up the money over the next ‘X’ months if a first time customer further converts to a repeat customer?</li>
</ul>
</ol>
</ol>
<p><a name="Repeat-Purchase-Rate"></a></p>
<h4><span style="color: #f7981d;"><strong>9. Repeat Purchase Rate</strong></span></h4>
<p>This metric relates to CLF (Customer Lifetime Value) metric above and is calculated as purchases from repeat customer divided by all purchases on the site for a given date range. It simply allows more ‘bites at the apple’ from media planning perspective.<br />
<a name="Revenue-Per-Session"></a></p>
<h4><span style="color: #f7981d;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">10. Revenue Per Session</span></span></h4>
<p>This is a must-have metric to measure and keep track of, as it enables you properly identify and set your store’s CPA (Cost-Per-Acquisition) and CPC (Cost-Per-Click) when launching CPC/CPA based traffic acquisition campaigns.</p>
<p>As an example: if you have 1,000 sessions (previously known as visits) to your web site and that generate $10,000 in revenue, then</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>Revenue Per Session = $10,000/1,000 = $10</strong></p>
<p>With that mind, and knowing that your profit margin was as an example: 20%, you may be willing to pay up to $2 per session (or click).</p>
<h4><span style="color: #f7981d;"><strong>Rounding Up</strong></span></h4>
<p>Although more data is typically always better than less, an overwhelming amount of data can frustrate and confuse even the most seasoned analysts. Aligning your focus on specific performance metrics is your only chance at extrapolating the most relevant pieces of information that really matter and drive business value.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #000000;">Kunle’s Bio:</span></h4>
<p>Kunle Campbell is a specialist eCommerce marketing consultant who works with mid-tier online retailers. He helps drive business growth and profitability through customer acquisition (driving traffic), conversion optimization and customer retention. All of his strategies are data and metric driven. You can read some more of Kunle’s articles on the company’s blog at <a href="http://www.2xmedia.co/" target="_blank">2x Media</a>. Also follow him on <a href="https://twitter.com/KunleTCampbell" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://plus.google.com/+KunleCampbell/" target="_blank">Google+</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/kunletcampbell" target="_blank">Facebook</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-essential-ecommerce-metrics-for-google-analytics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Free Ways to Learn How to Code Like an Ecommerce Developer</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-ways-to-learn-how-to-code-like-an-ecommerce-developer/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-ways-to-learn-how-to-code-like-an-ecommerce-developer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 15:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natalie Beigel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best Development Practices]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=18866</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Now more than ever, understanding computer programming is opening doors for endless opportunities – especially in the ecommerce space. Although you may not need to know how to code to bring an online store to life, it certainly helps to &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-ways-to-learn-how-to-code-like-an-ecommerce-developer/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now more than ever, understanding computer programming is opening doors for endless opportunities – especially in the ecommerce space. Although you may not need to know how to code to bring an online store to life, it certainly helps to achieve the results you really want.</p>
<p>Instead of outsourcing simple programming tasks to an expensive developer, you can learn how to do it yourself, for free! We’ve gathered 7 online resources that will teach you how to code from the luxury of your home.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-18867" title="7-resources-code" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/7-resources-code-1024x537.png" alt="" width="584" height="306" /></p>
<p><span id="more-18866"></span></p>
<h4>1. <a href="http://www.codecademy.com/" target="_blank">Codecademy</a></h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18882" title="1 codeacademy" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/1-codeacademy.png" alt="" width="575" height="314" /></p>
<p>Over 24 million learners are using <a href="http://www.codecademy.com/" target="_blank">Codecadamy</a> to learn how to code a website, an interactive website and Rails application. Learn all about HTML, Javascript, jQuery, Python, Ruby and PHP.</p>
<h4>2. <a href="https://www.udemy.com/courses/search/?q=coding&amp;p=1&amp;price=price-free&amp;view=grid" target="_blank">Udemy</a></h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18883" title="2 udemy" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/2-udemy.png" alt="" width="575" height="283" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.udemy.com/courses/search/?q=coding&amp;p=1&amp;price=price-free&amp;view=grid" target="_blank">Udemy</a> is the world’s online learning marketplace with over 4 million students. Each course is taught by an expert instructor and is available on-demand. Filter by instructional level and free courses to find the tutorial that fits your needs.</p>
<h4>3. <a href="http://thecodeplayer.com/ " target="_blank">TheCodePlayer</a></h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18884" title="3 the code player" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/3-the-code-player.png" alt="" width="575" height="281" /></p>
<p><a href="http://thecodeplayer.com/ " target="_blank">TheCodePlayer</a> offers video style walkthroughs of real examples. Learn HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and more. Each tutorial includes a video, live code viewer and related courses.</p>
<h4>4. <a href="http://www.w3schools.com/ " target="_blank">W3Schools.com</a></h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18885" title="4 w3schools" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/4-w3schools.png" alt="" width="575" height="276" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.w3schools.com/ " target="_blank">W3schools.com</a> has users from all over the world that want to learn how to code for free. Learn HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, PHP, jQuery, Angular, Bootstrap, XML and more. The tutorials contain examples and live online editors so you can edit the code and instantly see the results.</p>
<h4>5. <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/" target="_blank">Mozilla Developer Network</a></h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18879" title="5 mozilla developer network" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/5-mozilla-developer-network.png" alt="" width="575" height="256" /></p>
<p>Find helpful documentation for everything about the open Web on <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/" target="_blank">Mozilla Developer Network</a>. Learn all about web standards such as CSS, HTML and JavaScript on a platform that is constantly evolving with the latest information.</p>
<h4>6. <a href="https://www.coursera.org/ " target="_blank">Coursera</a></h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18880" title="6  coursera" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/6-coursera.png" alt="" width="575" height="330" /></p>
<p>Similar to Udemy, <a href="https://www.coursera.org/ " target="_blank">Coursera</a> offers courses in all types of subjects with dozens of free courses to learn how to program. The website offers courses in English, Chinese, Portuguese, Ukranian, Spanish, Russian and other languages. Learn the fundamentals or specialize in a specific type of programming language.</p>
<h4>7. <a href="http://teamtreehouse.com/ " target="_blank">Treehouse</a></h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18881" title="7 treehouse" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/7-treehouse.png" alt="" width="575" height="256" /></p>
<p><a href="http://teamtreehouse.com/ " target="_blank">Treehouse</a> offers a free 2-week trial to get started. Learn languages like HTML and CSS from your computer or mobile devices. Watch videos and then put your knowledge to the test with quizzes and Code Challenges. Learn freelance and business concepts and work towards a specific goal.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<p>Looking for more? Do a quick Google search to find local coding courses near you. Have you tried these resources before? Tell us what you think!</p>
<p>Put your coding skills to work by downloading <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">PrestaShop</a>, the world’s leading open source ecommerce solution, to create a free online store.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-ways-to-learn-how-to-code-like-an-ecommerce-developer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 New Ecommerce Themes for PrestaShop</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-new-ecommerce-themes-for-prestashop/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-new-ecommerce-themes-for-prestashop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 14:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natalie Beigel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=18777</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As soon as a customer visits your online store, your website design is the first thing that impacts your sales. From usability to colors, your ecommerce site must look and feel professional as soon as you launch. Not a designer? &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-new-ecommerce-themes-for-prestashop/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As soon as a customer visits your online store, your website design is the first thing that impacts your sales. From usability to colors, your ecommerce site must look and feel professional as soon as you launch.</p>
<p>Not a designer? Make a lasting impression with one of these 10 new ecommerce themes for PrestaShop stores. Each template is fully responsive, customizable, translatable, and compatible with version 1.6.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-18860" title="Header Image" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/Header-Image-1024x537.png" alt="Header" width="584" height="306" /></p>
<p><span id="more-18777"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #d64541;">Gadget Shop</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-18850" title="1. Gadget Shop" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/1.-Gadget-Shop.png" alt="Gadget Shop" width="575" height="373" /></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/high-tech/11449-new-gadgets-shop-responsive-html5-theme-16.html" target="_blank">Gadget Shop</a> offers a sleek design for enhanced usability. The theme includes advanced modules: stylish, customizable category images, a slider on the homepage, hover effect details, multiple product filters, featured products in the footer, and more.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d64541;">Leo Fashion Store</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-18851" title="2. Leo" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/2.-Leo.png" alt="Leo" width="575" height="651" /></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/fashion/11447-leo-fashion-store-prestashop.html" target="_blank">Leo Fashion Store</a> has a powerful framework supporting multiple layout options and dark and light color themes. The theme includes a friendly user experience by default and dozens of features such as: sliding featured products, hover flip and zoom effects and animated transitions.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d64541;">Cultura</span></h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18852" title="3. Cultura" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/3.-Cultura.png" alt="Cultura" width="575" height="357" /><br />
<a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/interior-furniture/14227-cultura-responsive-16.html" target="_blank">Cultura</a> is full of advanced features that add a modern flare to the minimalistic design. It’s intuitive navigation, clean product pages and flexible style makes it a perfect fit for any industry.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d64541;">Extreme Sports</span></h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18853" title="4. Extreme Sports" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/4.-Extreme-Sports.png" alt="Extreme Sports" width="575" height="391" /><br />
<a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/sport/17391-extreme-sports-clothing-gear.html" target="_blank">Extreme Sports</a> is an ideal template for any sporting goods business. The use of red elements draw a visitors’ attention to the most essential content. With custom blocks, advanced navigation and a top sellers side bar, this is a great template to launch an extreme sports store.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d64541;">Travely</span></h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18854" title="5. Travely" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/5.-Travely.png" alt="Travely" width="575" height="420" /><br />
<a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/travel/17643-travely-theme-shop-of-travel.html" target="_blank">Travely</a> comes complete with all the essential ecommerce website features. From a fixed mega menu to Google Maps, this stunning theme pays close attention to designer details. It also includes a free installation service from the developer.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d64541;">Shopster</span></h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18855" title="6. Shopster" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/6.-Shopster.png" alt="Shopster" width="575" height="509" /></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/high-tech/17699-shopster-content-first-responsive-prestashop-16.html" target="_blank">Shopster</a> is modern and simplistic with intuitive navigation. The theme is available in two versions, 3 and 4 columns, to arrange products to your liking. The fixed header scroll, sliding banner and product hover effects make it an adaptable template for most businesses.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d64541;">Oslo</span></h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18856" title="7. Oslo" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/7.-Oslo.png" alt="Oslo" width="575" height="414" /></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/fashion/16958-01-oslo.html" target="_blank">Oslo</a> is ideal for any trendsetting ecommerce business. Sleek with understated colors, the minimalist design emphasizes its ease of use. The theme is optimized for search engines with rich snippets on product pages, lightweight for fast loading time, and Multi-language ready to work with any language installed on your shop.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d64541;">Selling Furniture</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18857" title="8. Furniture Store" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/8.-Furniture-Store.png" alt="Furniture Store" width="575" height="500" /></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/interior-furniture/17880-selling-furniture-online.html" target="_blank">Selling Furniture</a> makes shopping an enjoyable experience. With a well-structured lay out, neat category displays and sleek promotional boxes, it’s easy for customers to find what they’re looking for.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d64541;">Supermarket</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18858" title="9. Supermarket" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/9.-Supermarket.png" alt="Supermarket" width="535" height="459" /></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/food-drinks/17741-supermarket-template.html" target="_blank">Supermarket</a> is a brilliant template for any online food store. The use of green colors and appealing large product images represent the concepts of natural, fresh and healthy. The vertical sidebar and banner categories make it easy to find products and encourages a purchase.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d64541;">Elation Advance Touch</span></h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18859" title="10. Elation" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/11/10.-Elation.png" alt="Elation" width="575" height="348" /></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/neutral/16704-elation-advance-touch-theme.html" target="_blank">Elation Advance Touch</a> offers full creative control with unlimited colors, layouts and fonts. This template is beautifully designed with sliders, banners and parallax effect background images. It also includes advanced SEO features to help your site rank high on search results. To make things even easier, the developer shares a high-def video tutorial explaining how to install and customize every piece of the theme.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h4><span style="color: #d64541;">Want to see more?</span></h4>
<p>Visit <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Addons</a> and find more than 1,500 ecommerce themes to customize your PrestaShop store. Segmented by category, compatibility, colors and columns, you’ll quickly find what you need!</p>
<p>Using one of the templates above? Comment below and share your feedback with the community.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-new-ecommerce-themes-for-prestashop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Simple Growth Hacks for Ecommerce Customer Acquisition</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-simple-growth-hacks-for-ecommerce-customer-acquisition/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-simple-growth-hacks-for-ecommerce-customer-acquisition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 14:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natalie Beigel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=18763</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So you have an online store with great products, now what? The success of your business depends on bringing in customers. But how can you attract those customers without cash flow and brand recognition? Growth hacking. Simply put, growth hacking &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-simple-growth-hacks-for-ecommerce-customer-acquisition/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So you have an online store with great products, now what? The success of your business depends on bringing in customers. But how can you attract those customers without cash flow and brand recognition? Growth hacking.</p>
<p>Simply put, growth hacking tactics are an inexpensive and innovative alternative to traditional marketing. And it’s how you can build awareness and reduce your customer acquisition costs to nearly $0.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-18839" title="main" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/main-1024x537.png" alt="" width="584" height="306" /></p>
<p><span id="more-18763"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #65c6bb;">Introduction</span></h4>
<p>Growth hacking has undoubtedly been the driving force behind some of the most successful startups. Companies such as Air B&amp;B, YouTube, Dropbox and Groupon are all early adopters of <a href="https://www.ventureharbour.com/ultimate-startup-marketing-strategy/" target="_blank">growth hacking strategies</a>. Clearly, it’s working.</p>
<p>Now, how can you do it too? Let’s review 3 simple growth hacks that ecommerce sites use to grow their customer base. Through social media, search engine, rich content and viral marketing, you’ll be able to squeeze more out of the time and effort spent acquiring new customers.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #2574a9;">Customer Refer Customer</span></h2>
<h4><span style="color: #65c6bb;">“Refer a friend and get $25 towards your next purchase!”</span></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18832" title="Customer Refer Customer" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/Customer-Refer-Customer.png" alt="" width="575" height="319" /></p>
<p><span style="color: #2574a9;"><strong>Why it works:</strong></span> Refer a friend programs develop a sense of reciprocity between you and your customer. Since generally refer a friend programs require that the referral makes a purchase/subscribes, a customer feels obliged to refer a qualified lead to guarantee they will be rewarded.</p>
<p><span style="color: #2574a9;"><strong>What to test:</strong></span> Try different incentives and offer them at different stages of the customer’s lifecycle to find out what works best. Here are few examples of referral incentives:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">• “Refer 3 friends and get a free gift package”<br />
• “Invite 5 friends and get 3 months of free shipping”<br />
• “Invite friends and earn 300 loyalty points!”<br />
• “Refer a friend and get 1 month free subscription”</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #2574a9;">Connect with Influencers</span></h2>
<h4><span style="color: #65c6bb;">Engage online influencers that are key players in your niche</span></h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18833" title="Influencer Image" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/Influencer-Image1.png" alt="" width="575" height="400" /></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #2574a9;">Why it works:</span></strong> Building relationships and incentivizing influencers such as bloggers, journalists, experts to give you coverage introduces your online business to their entire audience. If you picked the <a href="http://www.socialmediaelearning.co.uk/social-media-influencers-find-engage-grow-your-business/" target="_blank">right influencers</a> then you just opened the doors to an exponential number of potential customers. This strategy also creates back links to your website, augmenting your SEO efforts.</p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #2574a9;">Where to start:</span></strong> Start small. Convincing a major influencer to give you coverage doesn’t happen over night. Begin by reaching out to non-celebrity bloggers that have a strong social media presence then work your way to the top!</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #2574a9;">Social Prospecting</span></h2>
<h4><span style="color: #65c6bb;">Engage potential customers via digital guerilla marketing</span></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18834" title="EN_Social Prospecting" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/EN_Social-Prospecting.png" alt="" width="470" height="241" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18835" title="EN_SocialProspecting2" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/EN_SocialProspecting2.png" alt="" width="470" height="267" /></p>
<p><span style="color: #2574a9;"><strong>Why it works:</strong></span> You’re connecting with social media users that are speaking out about your specific industry, product or niche market. This means they are already interested! By providing personal attention with a helpful response, you are presenting your business as a valuable resource.</p>
<p><span style="color: #2574a9;"><strong>How to do it:</strong></span> Do a quick daily search on Twitter for #hashtags and conversations related to your business. Then tweet at these prospects that have used the hashtag with helpful advice and a link to your site or a relevant blog post. You should focus on being resourceful rather than salesy. You don’t want these potential customers to think your spamming them. For a complete guide, check out Hubspot’s <a href="http://offers.hubspot.com/social-prospecting-workbook" target="_blank">Social Prospecting Workbook</a>.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<p>Customer acquisition is all about finding what works best for your target audience. It’s also an area of your business where you should constantly be testing new strategies. Who knows, it might be one of these growth hacks that turn your business into a hit!</p>
<p>Have you tried any growth hacking tactics for customer acquisition? Share your experience and advice in the comments below.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-simple-growth-hacks-for-ecommerce-customer-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>15 Examples of CTA buttons to drive conversions for online stores</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/15-examples-of-cta-buttons-to-drive-conversions-for-online-stores/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/15-examples-of-cta-buttons-to-drive-conversions-for-online-stores/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 16:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=18802</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Earlier this year we showed you the importance of call to action (CTA) buttons, emphasizing the significance of placement, size, shape, color and text. What works and what doesn’t? Today, we share 15 examples of CTA buttons to drive conversions &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/15-examples-of-cta-buttons-to-drive-conversions-for-online-stores/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this year we showed you <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-importance-of-call-to-action-buttons-on-your-e-commerce-site/" target="_blank">the importance of call to action (CTA) buttons</a>, emphasizing the significance of placement, size, shape, color and text. What works and what doesn’t? Today, we share 15 examples of CTA buttons to drive conversions for online stores.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-18804" title="CTA" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/CTA-1024x537.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="306" /></p>
<p>Using examples from PrestaShop stores, we’ll show you CTA’s that convert with pop-ups, social engagement, home page features and most importantly, product page design. Let’s get started!</p>
<p><span id="more-18802"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #009bdf;">CTA buttons in pop-ups</span></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-pop-ups-for-your-online-store-best-practices-and-examples-for-2015/" target="_blank">Pop-ups in online stores</a> can be very effective in drawing a shopper’s attention to a specific CTA. They feature a box or window on top of other page content to increase conversion. See how these shops use pop-ups:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18805" title="01 whatgoesaroundnyc" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/01-whatgoesaroundnyc.png" alt="" width="500" height="374" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.whatgoesaroundnyc.com/ " target="_blank">What Goes Around NYC</a> encourages its customers to sign up for their membership only shop by using this well-timed popup. This pop up only appears after a customer shows interest by clicking on a product &#8211; rather than being displayed immediately.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18806" title="02 teaguys" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/02-teaguys.png" alt="" width="500" height="324" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.teaguys.com/ " target="_blank">Tea Guys</a> approaches pop-ins differently. This pop-up only opens if a customer clicks on the review tab. Once it appears, Tea Guys effectively encourages customers to leave reviews by prominently displaying the “Write a Review” CTA above the fold.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #009bdf;">CTA’s that leverage social trust</span></h2>
<p>To convert visitors into social media followers, these PrestaShop merchants leverage social trust. Social trust stems from the assumption that if lots of people like a company, they must be trustworthy. See how these merchant convert new fans by leveraging their current fan base.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18807" style="color: #333333; font-style: normal; line-height: 24.375px;" title="03 headict.co.uk" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/03-headict.co_.uk_.png" alt="" width="500" height="275" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.headict.co.uk/ " target="_blank">Headict</a> displays social media buttons with a counter displaying the number of fans they currently have. With over 8,000 followers across their three social media platforms, it’s easy to trust this brand and hop on the bandwagon.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18808" title="04 29nUnder" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/04-29nUnder.png" alt="" width="500" height="224" /></p>
<p><a href="http://29nunder.com/ " target="_blank">29NUnder</a> not only builds trust with their over 112k followers on Facebook, they make it effortless for you to become a fan. Customers simply need to click the “like” button. No new windows, no sign ups.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #009bdf;">Engaging CTA’s on home pages</span></h2>
<p>Home pages for your online store should draw your audience in and entice them to learn more. These shops encourage visitors to learn more about their products with great images and minimal text.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18809" title="05 adelineaffre" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/05-adelineaffre.png" alt="" width="500" height="329" /></p>
<p><a href="http://adelineaffre.com/en/ " target="_blank">Adelineaffre</a> shows off their products by displaying them in action, or in this case in a home. Seeing how products can be integrated into a customer’s life draws them in and encourages them to learn more.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18810" title="06 lindenleaves" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/06-lindenleaves.png" alt="" width="500" height="263" /></p>
<p><a href="http://lindenleaves.com/ " target="_blank">Linden Leaves</a> uses their home page to feature their natural skincare line. They draw attention away from the model and drives the shoppers’ focus to the products by putting the products directly in her line of sight.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #009bdf;">Effective CTA’s on product pages</span></h2>
<p>Although CTA’s are important throughout your website, the most important CTA’s are on your<a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-examples-of-ecommerce-product-pages-that-convert/ " target="_blank"> product pages.</a> This call to action is very important because it is the customer’s first step in making a purchase.  With that said, we’re sharing great product page CTA’s and breaking down their copy (text), decoration, location and overall page design.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><span style="color: #000000; text-decoration: underline;">Great copy</span></strong></span></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18811" title="07 bettereverafter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/07-bettereverafter.png" alt="" width="500" height="277" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.bettereverafter.com/112-adventure-in-the-city.html " target="_blank">BetterEverAfter</a>’s product page targets brides building a wedding registry. To highlight this, they use “Add to Registry” rather than “Add to wish list”, making this page perfectly tailored for its target audience.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18812" title="08 funkylama" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/08-funkylama.png" alt="" width="500" height="301" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.funky-lama.com/en/2247-little-handpuppet-crocodile.html " target="_blank">Funky Lama</a> creates a sense urgency in purchasing their products by including the following message next to the CTA, “Last items in stock!” Want more words that urge customers to purchase? Try “limited time”, “today” or “now”.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #000000;"><strong>Emphasized with borders</strong></span></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-18813" title="09 lafolleadresse" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/09-lafolleadresse.png" alt="" width="589" height="340" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.lafolleadresse.com/331-carte-postale-darling-clementine-ooh-la-la-.html " target="_blank">La folle adresse</a> decorates their call to action with a cute icon and a thick dotted border. The decoration is far enough away from the product image so it does not distract, but is highlighted enough to draw your attention towards it.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18814" title="10 myindiesoul" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/10-myindiesoul.png" alt="" width="500" height="316" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.myindiesoul.com/boho-bags/356-dunes.html " target="_blank">Indie Soul</a> also highlights their CTA button with a border. However, they matched it to their theme by using only a simple but dark border.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>Location, location, location</strong></span></span></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18815" title="11 moncolonel.fr" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/11-moncolonel.fr_.png" alt="" width="500" height="368" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.moncolonel.fr/en/table-ware/254-bunol-collection-.html?search_query=bunol&amp;results=1 " target="_blank">Mon Colonel</a> displays their CTA above the fold, making it easy for customers to find. This is especially important for products with lengthy product descriptions. As an added bonus they highlight this button using their web page’s accent color.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18816" title="12 eatingtools" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/12-eatingtools.png" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></p>
<p>Although <a href="https://www.eatingtools.com/one-of-a-kind/48-the-osage-scoop.html" target="_blank">Eating Tools</a> places their CTA after the product description, the short description allows it to easily sit above the fold. Aside from the location, this CTA’s size and boldness ensures customers can’t miss it.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Overall page design</span></strong></span></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18817" title="13 bobbies.fr" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/13-bobbies.fr_.png" alt="" width="500" height="321" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.bobbies.fr/en/boots-femme-la-muse/2141204607-boots-fauve-la-muse.html " target="_blank">Bobbies</a> displays their products on a magazine inspired product page and uses their accent color to feature the CTA button. To further highlight it, they grayed out neighboring payment logos. The best thing about this CTA is that although your eyes are drawn to the CTA button, it seamlessly blends in with the overall design of the product page.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18818" title="14 creedboutique" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/14-creedboutique.png" alt="" width="500" height="340" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.creedboutique.com/creed-perfume-for-men/116-creed-aventus-871854009347.html " target="_blank">Creed Boutique</a> also seamlessly integrates their call to action button into their product page. They achieved this without accent colors by simply inverting the CTA button’s colors. The contrast helps shoppers easily spot the button to encourage shopping.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18819" title="15 addons" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/15-addons.png" alt="" width="500" height="309" /></p>
<p>Of course we couldn’t forget the online store for PrestaShop’s official modules and themes, <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/front-office-features-prestashop-modules/2191-box-notification-popup.html " target="_blank">PrestaShop Addons.</a> Our Add to cart button is featured above the fold, making it easily accessible. Additionally, it’s located far from other graphics to ensure it doesn’t detract from product images.</p>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
<p>Which of these examples of CTA buttons will inspire the ones on your online shop? Share your favorites – or any we may have missed &#8211; in the comments below. Not an online merchant yet? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download " target="_blank">Download PrestaShop</a> to start selling online!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/15-examples-of-cta-buttons-to-drive-conversions-for-online-stores/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to harness eBay for cross-border sales</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-harness-ebay-for-cross-border-sales/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-harness-ebay-for-cross-border-sales/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 14:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16098</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you’re an online merchant looking to expand your success, look no further than selling internationally. As consumers become more connected, they want the ability to buy anytime anywhere. It’s why cross-border transactions (CBT) has become a large opportunity of &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-harness-ebay-for-cross-border-sales/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’re an online merchant looking to expand your success, look no further than selling internationally. As consumers become more connected, they want the ability to<strong> buy anytime anywhere.</strong> It’s why cross-border transactions (CBT) has become a large opportunity of growth for merchants.</p>
<p>Did you know that cross-border online trade between the 6 largest markets in the world is estimated to be worth over <strong>£1 billion annually </strong>and this figure is predicted to triple by 2018. But before you start localizing your website for every country and language, it’s important to test international markets.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-18752" title="ebay-cross-border-trade" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/10/ebayblog-1024x537.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="306" /> <span id="more-16098"></span></p>
<p>Although testing international markets may sound expensive, we have great news to share. Not only is it affordable, you can even make money while learning about the international demand for the products you sell through your online store.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #e33238;">Cross-border trade through online marketplaces</span></h2>
<p>By leveraging a marketplace, you can easily expand your reach into countless international markets. Marketplaces like eBay gives you access to over 149 million active buyers worldwide. Listing products on eBay’s international marketplace, helps you reach 20% of their buyers who regularly purchase from international sellers – with the remaining 80% saying they’d do so for the right product.</p>
<p>Selling on eBay helps you build a feedback history making it the best first step to cross-border sales. After each sale on eBay, buyers can leave feedback – consisting of a rating and short comment. Based on this feedback, sellers can improve their product descriptions, customer service, shipping options and pricing – to name a few.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #0065d1;">Choosing where to sell</span></h2>
<p>Which countries should you target? It depends. Generally, your target market should have a high adoptions rate of online shopping, with limited domestic sellers. However, to determine if your product(s) are right for your selected markets, start by selling through a marketplace. Once you’ve completed sales, you’ll know which counties you should sell to and optimize for.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #85b716;">Getting started with marketplaces</span></h2>
<p>Depending on your shop and the number of products you sell, there are different ways to get started. Smaller businesses with a limited number of products, can start by listing products and offering to ship internationally. When customers browse and search eBay’s catalog, your products will be made available.</p>
<p>Medium-sized businesses with a substantial catalog of products, can open an eBay Shop.* In addition to listing your products for millions of users to purchase, you can create a fully-customized central shopping destination for your products to build your brand. You can also boost sales with marketing tools and list your products for longer at more cost effective prices.</p>
<p>To take advantage of all these features, import your products effortlessly with <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/marketplace-prestashop-modules/2742-ebay.html " target="_blank">eBay’s free module</a>. The eBay module was recently updated to help PrestaShop merchants effortlessly master cross-border trade.</p>
<address>*Please note that only Top Shop and Premium shops (DE), Boutique A la Une and Boutique Premium (FR), Negozio Premium and Negozio Premium Plus (IT) or Tienda Avanzada and Tienda Premium (ES) types of shops on eBay have international selling capabilities.</address>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-harness-ebay-for-cross-border-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced
Object Caching 826/980 objects using disk: basic

Served from: www.prestashop.com @ 2014-11-25 18:56:02 -->